银白的雪花
Inside a snowflake, like the one on your sleeve...
片片地落下
其中深藏着一个故事
...there happened a story you must see to believe.
在遥远的松饼山上
Way up in the mountains, in the high range of Pontoos...
有着一个小镇
...lay the small town of Whoville:
片名：鬼灵精 那就是胡谷镇
The home of the Whos.
随便问一位胡谷镇民
Ask any Who, and they'll have this to say:
他们会告诉你 胡谷镇的圣诞节是最棒的
"There is no place like Whoville around Christmas Day."
到处张灯结彩、喜气洋洋
Every window was flocked, every lamppost was dressed...
乐队换上了大礼服，穿街过市
...and the Whoville band marched in their Christmasy best.
圣诞快乐，圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas! Merry Christmas!
植树节不错，复活节也很棒
Arbor Day was fine, and Easter was pleasant...
每次圣泡沫节就吃泡沫雉
...and every Saint Fizzin's day, they ate a Fizz pheasant.
但每位胡谷镇民打心眼知道
But every Who knew, from their twelve toes to their snout...
毫无疑问地
...they loved Christmas the most, without a single Who doubt.
圣诞节才是他们的最爱
欢迎光临 多谢惠顾
- Farfingle's welcomes you! - Thank you.
圣诞快乐！欢迎光临
Merry Christmas! Thank you for shopping Farfingle's!
我们帮你大哥买了电话
We got a snoozlephone for your brother Drew...
帮你二哥也买了电话
...and a snoozlephone for your brother Stu, a muncle for your uncle...
运动器材给你舅
裤子给你舅妈
...a fant for your aunt and a fandpa for your cousin Leon.
皮鞋给你表哥
我们只要再…辛蒂？
So, we just need... Cindy?
特价品在三楼
Sale on Aisle 3!
辛蒂… 圣诞快乐
- Cindy Lou! - Merry Christmas.
嗨，麦纳，圣诞快乐
Hello, Myrna. Merry Christmas, Fred. Excuse me.
麻烦，借过 辛蒂？女儿
Cindy Lou? Honey?
爸，是不是买太多了
- Dad? - Yeah?
Doesn't this seem like a bit much?
圣诞节本来就该这样
This is what Christmas is all about!
感觉到了吗？
Can't you feel it?
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas!
多谢惠顾…等一下
Thank you for shopping Farfingle's. Wait a second!
还没找钱
Your change!
圣诞节越来越近了
Another minute closer to Christmas!
圣诞大拍卖，限时五分钟
And, for the next five minutes only, 99 percent off!
的确，胡谷镇的每位镇民 都喜欢圣诞节
Yes, every Who down in Whoville liked Christmas a lot...
但住在胡谷镇以北的鬼灵精
...but the Grinch, who lived just north of Whoville...
正好相反
...did not.
告诉你们，漂亮的w寄生在山顶
Get on it, girls. All the good mistletoe's at the top.
朱朱，我们来比赛
- Hey, Drew, I'll race you! - Not if I race you first.
你跑不赢我的 最慢的是猪头
Last one to the top is a stinky old Grinch!
我们到底在哪？
You guys, where are we? I think we should go back.
还是回去算了 干嘛？你怕鬼灵精
What? You're scared of the Grinch!
才没有
No!
听说他就住在山顶
They say he lives up here in a big cave.
只有肚子饿的时候才会下山来…
And only comes down when he's hungry for the taste of...
吃人  别闹了
- ...Who flesh! - Drew!
喂！  你怕鬼灵精
You're scared of the Grinch! You're scared of the Grinch!
你怕鬼灵精
“闲杂人”
胆小鬼 才不是
- Are too! - Am not!
等我
Wait for me!
快点，快敲门
Go on, touch it. Touch the door.
你不爱我吗？小史
Do it for me, Stu.
干得好，麦斯
Well done, Max!
活该，爱过节的小鬼
Serves them right, those Yuletide-loving...
叽叽喳喳、肉麻兮兮
...sickly-sweet, nog-sucking cheer mongers!
我讨厌他们，非常讨厌
I really don't like them.
No, I don't.
麦斯！
Max!
拿我的披风来
Get my cloak!
我对山下那群死白痴
I've been much too tolerant of these Whovenile delinquents...
已经够客气的了
...and their innocent, victimless pranks.
他们想认识我，是不是
So, they want to get to know me, do they?
他们想了解我，鬼灵精
They want to spend a little quality time with the Grinch.
看来不出去晃晃
I guess I could use a little...
是不行了
...social interaction.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas!
是啊！你也一样 圣诞快乐个屁
Yeah, you bet.
Ho, ho, ho, and stuff.
天哪！有人出车祸了
Oh, my.
Someone has vandalized that vehicle.
看到没？麦斯 马路如虎口
You see, Max? The city is a dangerous place.
鬼灵精讨厌圣诞节
The Grinch hated Christmas. The whole Christmas season.
你好啊！条子 不要问我为什么
Top of the day. Flatfoot.
Now, please, don't ask why. No one quite knows the reason.
因为没有人知道 小朋友，送给你们
Here's a present for you.
不用慢慢走，用跑的，跑快点
Be sure to run real fast with it. Come on. Double time. Move.
不是因为他有根筋不对劲
It could be that his head wasn't screwed on just right.
就是因为他的鞋子太紧了
Or it could be, perhaps, that his shoes were too tight.
我认为唯一的可能… 圣诞快乐
But I think that the most likely reason of all...
白痴 是他的心胸…
...may have been that his heart was two sizes too small.
实在太狭窄了
老兄，进来买顶帽子吧
Stranger, won't let you go till you buy a chapeau!
圣诞节是不是很棒？
Boy, nothing beats Christmas, right?
大概吧
I guess.
大概？
You guess?
因为我只看到你和妈 还有其他人大买特买
It's just, I look around at you and Mom and everyone getting all curbobbled.
你不觉得夸张吗？
Doesn't this seem superfluous?
爸爸！
Dad!
你们怎么啦？ 碰到鬼灵精了
- What happened to you? - It was the Grinch!
鬼灵精？
- Grinch? - What do you want? I mean...
叫我干嘛？我是说…
鬼灵精？好可怕！
"Grinch? Oh, no!"
是谁在说鬼灵精？
Did someone just say, "Grinch"?
镇长大人，您好
Hello, Mayor May-Who, sir.
Lou.
我想你一定知道 今年的圣诞节
I don't need to remind you that this Christmas...
正好是建镇一千年纪念
...marks the one thousandth Whobilation.
是本镇最重要的日子 根据“胡谷镇民手册”
Whoville's most important celebration!
上面写得非常清楚
And The Book of Who says, very clearly:
镇民无论男女老幼
"Every size of Who we can measure...
都必须重视此一节日
"...knows that Whobilation is a time we must treasure."
麻烦你告诉我
Now, Lou, please tell me that your boys...
你儿子没有跑上山
...were not up on Mount Crumpit...
骚扰那个住在松饼山峰 讨厌圣诞节的怪物
...provoking the one creature within a billion bilometers of here...
可是真的是他…
...who hates Christmas!
But it was the Grinch!
误会，一场误会 他们啥都没看到
No, sir, the boys didn't see any Grinch.
他们大概只是上山
It was, and he came after--
I think they were up on the mountain...
玩玩火柴、砍砍树什么的
...playing with matches, or defacing public property, or...
太好了
这样我就放心了
That's a relief.
各位，都听到啦 鬼灵精警报解除
All right, you heard the man:
There is no Grinch problem here.
“胡谷镇邮局” 阿卢，限时专送
- I need it there by tomorrow. - Heck of a rush.
行，限时专送
你好，圣诞快乐，限时专送
Merry Christmas, Mo. Heck of a rush.
爸，有一件事我不懂
But, Dad...
...I just don't understand something.
为什么大家都怕鬼灵精？
Why won't anyone talk about the Grinch?
小孩就是小孩
You kids and the Grinch!
辛蒂，鬼灵精是胡谷镇民
You see, Cindy, the Grinch is a Who, who always...
也不能算是，那家伙…
Actually, not a Who. He's more of a...
怎样？ 对了，宝贝
- A what? - Exactly, honey.
那家伙讨厌圣诞节
And he's a What who doesn't like Christmas.
你看他的信箱
Take a look at his mailbox, sweetie.
空的，连张圣诞卡都没有
Not a single Christmas card, in or out.
为什么呢？ 我的信呢？阿卢
Ever!
But why?
Lou, where's my mail?
这封信不是我的 阿卢，送错信了
Lou! Got the wrong mail here.
Lou! I got the wrong mail!
我来了  出问题了
- I'll be right there. - Lou, we got a problem!
别担心，我来搞定
All right, we'll straighten this out.
他们得花几年才搞得定
It'll take them years to sort this out.
他的送给你，你的送给她
This is his and now it's yours, and this hers and now it's his!
至于其他人呢
And for the rest of you:
法院通知、法院通知
Jury duty! Jury duty! Jury duty!
恐吓信、解聘书 连锁信、逐客令
Blackmail. Pink slip. Chain letter. Eviction notice.
法院通知
Jury duty!
帮爸爸拿到后面好吗？
Would you mind helping me take this to the back room, honey?
小心分信机哦 知道
- Be careful of the sorting machine, right? - Yeah.
感冒啦…
Gesundheit.
你是…是…
You're the...
是…是…鬼灵精
The...
The Grinch!
救命！
这招蛮管用的
救命啊！
That worked out nicely.
Help!
“小心轻放”
快救我 我们走，麦斯
Help me! Somebody!
Max, let's go.
事情办完啦
Our work here is finished.
求求你，救救我
Help me!
我的屁屁可不是给你磨牙的
Please help!
That is not a chew toy!
别闹了，你有完没完
Stop it, Max!
搞什么？很痛耶
Get that out of your mouth! You have no idea where it's been!
救命啊！
Help!
不能见死不救
Bleeding hearts of the world, unite!
上来
好了，还来
There! Give me that!
你没听过物归原主吗？
Don't you know you shouldn't take things that don't belong to you?
干嘛？想占为己有啊？
What's your problem? Are you a wild animal?
我们走
Let's go.
谢谢你救我
Thanks for saving me.
“出口”
救你？
Saving you?
你以为我是要救你？
Is that what you think I was doing?
错
Wrong-o.
我是发现你包装不合格
I merely noticed that you were improperly packaged, my dear.
站好
Hold still!
麦斯，拿缎带
Max, pick out a bow.
手指借一下
Can I use your finger for a second?
有人在吗？
Hello! Hello!
女儿？
- Cindy? - Dad!
爸…
Daddy!
怎么搞的？
What the hey...?
女儿
Honey.
爸，太棒了 你在练习包装礼物
Cindy?
Dad! It was amazing!
You've been practicing your Christmas wrapping!
我真是太高兴了 其实…
I am so proud of you.
这才像过节嘛
Now, that's holiday.
小辛蒂不知该如何是好
Sweet little Cindy didn't know what to do.
她的心中充满了疑问
In her head, bum-tumbled a conflict or two.
鬼灵精不是很坏吗？ 为什么还要救我？
"If the Grinch was so bad, then why did he save me?
也许他并不是坏人 我们回家吧
"Maybe he wasn't so bad."
也许，只是也许
Maybe. Just maybe.
灯没开，你妈大概出去了
No lights on in the house. Your mom must be shopping.
太好了，你们回来了
Good, I'm so glad you're home.
老公，我有预感，就是今年
I can feel it, Lou. This is the year.
大家只要问到
When everybody asks who has the most spectacular lights in greater Whoville...
谁家的圣诞灯饰最美丽
就会说，贝蒂卢女士
...they're gonna cry out, "Mrs. Betty Lou Who!"
这不是餐厅的吊灯吗？
Isn't this the chandelier from the dining room?
你就委屈一下吧
It's all for the cause, dear.
好吧 还有，女儿
And Cindy? Could you be Mommy's little helper...
去帮妈妈把冰箱的灯泡拆下来
...and unscrew the bulb there from the refrigerator?
我忘了拆 去吧
- 'Cause somehow I missed that one. - Go on!
每一年
Every year Martha May Whovier has the best lights.
灯饰比赛都是梅玛莎赢
但是今年她别想
Not this year.
我一定会打败那个三八…
This year...
...I'm gonna beat that prim, perfect little prissy--
贝蒂，嗨
Betty!
- Hi! - Martha!
玛莎
天啊，这是我看过 最美丽的圣诞灯饰
My, I've never seen so many beautiful Christmas lights, Betty Lou!
是啊，我是在向你看齐嘛
I'd blow every fuse if I tried to keep up with you, Martha May!
是不是很漂亮？是手工做的
Isn't this antique darling?
It's handcrafted and almost 100 years old.
这可是古董哦
对啊，美死了 这可是新买的
Jeez. I'm really impressed!
This, however, is new.
喂，贝蒂，老婆
Betty! Sweetie!
晚安啦，贝蒂
Good night, Betty.
我接 老婆，我接了
- I got it! - Honey, I've got it.
Hello?
我的冷气机是不是坏了？
Is my sub-zero chillibrator running?
没有吧 那你还不打开
- I suppose. - You better go catch it!
笑死我了，我真幽默
That's a good one! That is rich.
回家吧！
Let's go home.
不好意思，长幼有序
Fleas before beauty. Thank you.
快点，慢吞吞的
Come on, hurry up, Slowpoke.
“往松饼山垃圾场”
应该有别的捷径
There's got to be a better way!
坐车就不用这么辛苦了
A car would have paid for itself by now!
好耶，另外一批货
Goody. Another load coming down.
哇，有够臭
What's that stench?
正合我意
It's fantastic!
“危险废料”
先拿一袋，剩下的待会再拿
Max! Grab a bag.
We'll come back for the rest.
也就是说，待会你来拿
Of course, when I say "we," I mean "you."
这些镇民有够浪费的
It's amazing what these Whos just throw away.
反正咧
Oh, well.
你丢我捡，废物利用
One man's toxic sludge is another man's potpourri.
罗唆，我是能省就省
I don't know. It's some kind of soap.
为何不见
"Where are you, Christmas?
圣诞影踪
"Why can't I find you?
为何音讯全无
"Why have you gone away?
世界在变
"My world is changing
我在改变
"I'm rearranging
不知圣诞
"Does that mean Christmas
是否依旧
"changes too?
“圣诞老人 我不知道我要什么”
为何不见
"Where are you, Christmas?
圣诞影踪
"Do you remember
是否忘了我
"The girl you used to know?
过去
"You and I were so carefree
美好回忆
仍在梦中
"Now nothing's easy
不知圣诞
"Did Christmas change
是否
"Or just
依旧
"me?"
厉害
Sweet!
我的家庭真可爱
"Be it ever so
整洁美满又安康
"Heinous
"There's no place like home"
一楼，厕所
First floor, factory rejects.
那些镇民神经可真粗
Those Whos are hard to frazzle, Max!
反正我们已经尽力了
But we did our worst. And that's all that matters.
至少那个小女孩被我吓得半死
At least I scared the bejeebles out of that little girl at the post office.
搞不好需要收惊
She'll be scarred for life, if we're lucky.
她居然没去告密
Funny she didn't rat on us, though.
八成怕我报复
Must be afraid of reprisals.
耶！小了一号半
Yes!
Down a size and a half!
这次我要保持下去
And this time, I'll keep it off.
麦斯，去捡回来
Get the stick, Max. Get the stick!
捡得到才怪
There's no stick!
真好骗
I'm smarter.
有留言吗？
Any calls?
无人留言
You have no messages.
怪了，难道没录音
Odd. Better check the outgoing.
你最好没打错
If you utter so much as one syllable...
否则你就倒大霉了
...I'll hunt you down and gut you like a fish!
传真的话，请按米字键
If you'd like to fax me, press the star key.
好吧
Oh, well.
舒服多了
That's more like it.
愉快的一年
Excellent year.
告诉你，麦斯 我根本不需要出门
I'll tell you, Max...
...I don't know why I ever leave this place.
我在家有聊的很
I've got all the company I need right here.
喂
Hello!
你好吗？
How are you?
是我先问的
I asked you first.
学我讲话 你以为你很幽默吗？
That's really mature, saying exactly what I say!
Mature... exactly... what I say...
我是白痴 你是白痴
I'm an idiot!
You're an idiot!
算你厉害，我不跟你讲话
All right, fine.
我自己跟自己讲
I'm not talking to you anymore. In fact, I'm going to whisper.
就算我的声音撞到墙
So that by the time my voice reverberates off the walls and gets back to me...
再弹回来
我也听不到
...I won't be able to hear it!
你是白痴
You're an idiot!
我不是在借吃浇愁吧？
Am I just eating because I'm bored?
会是谁呢？
Who could that be?
小妹妹 你是来念书给我们听的？
Hello, little girl. Are you here to read to us?
不是，听说你们认识鬼灵精
No.
I hear you know some things about the Grinch.
“鬼灵精在胡谷镇附近出没”
Cindy Lou had some questions in her curious heart.
辛蒂心中充满了疑问
鬼灵精为什么会讨厌圣诞节
Why did the Grinch hate Christmas? Where did it all start?
有了录音机，她就不怕了
With her dad's blabbacorder she wouldn't give an inch.
请详细叙述你和鬼灵精 认识的经过
In your own words, please tell me everything you know about the Grinch.
他从哪来的？ 是这样的
Where did he come from?
他和其他胡谷宝宝一样
He came the way all Who babies come.
在一个月黑风高的夜晚
On calm nights...
胡谷镇的宝宝们
...baby Who girls and tiny Who fellas...
坐着雨伞摇篮，从天而降
...drift from the sky in their own pumbersellas.
老婆，我们的宝宝来了
Hey, honey, our baby is here!
怎么长得像你老板
He looks just like your boss.
原来如此
So that's how it works.
那天是平安夜，窗外吹着怪风
It was Christmas Eve, and a strange wind blew that night.
我们正在开圣诞舞会
We were having our annual holiday get-together.
到了早上才发现他在外面
It was morning before anybody realized that he was out there!
可怜的宝宝
The poor dear!
你知道吗？
But, you know what?
我们马上就晓得他与众不同
We knew right away that he was special.
要不要圣诞饼干？
Do you want a Christmas cookie?
你想要哪一块？ 圣诞老人
Yes, which Christmas cookie would you like?
Santa.
他说话了
His first words!
对，碟子上是圣诞老人
Yes, that is a Santa plate.
你要不要拿啊？
Do you want to hold this Santa plate?
圣诞老人，再见
Santa, bye-bye!
他是个乖宝…
He was a wonderful...
…怪宝宝
...whatever he was.
我们和胡谷镇其他的父母一样
And we raised him like any other Who child:
教小孩要喜欢圣诞节
With a deep love of Christmas.
记得，明天要交换圣诞礼物
Don't forget, tomorrow is our big Christmas gift exchange.
每个人准备一份特别的礼物送人
Everyone bring a special gift for a special someone.
鬼灵精？
The...
...Grinch...
他对配色毫无概念
He had no sense of color coordination.
我不太记得他，念书都来不及了
Although I hardly remember him. I didn't have time to socialize.
哪有时间交朋友
I was far too busy with my...
...studies.
各位同学，写完了没
Now, class, is everyone almost finished?
大家都说，他喜欢玛莎
And if the truth be told, he...
He liked Martha.
玛莎是我的女朋友
Martha was my girlfriend.
我不想谈鬼灵精的事
I don't like discussing this Grinch so very close to Christmas, but...
快过圣诞节了
我想你也听说了…
...maybe if you hear the truth, you'll understand why--
你没吃饭啊
Put your back into it!
一直是我在罩他
I tried to take him under my wing.
她不会喜欢你的，你脸上都是毛
You don't have a chance with her. You're 8 years old and you have a beard!
他长了一身毛
He had hair. Not pleasant.
而且还到处掉
He shed.
Not right.
知道吗？我最喜欢圣诞节了
You know, Christmas is my favorite time of year.
尤其是那些颜色
I just love the colors.
红色，还有绿色
The red...
...and the green.
我是不是暗恋鬼灵精？
Did I have a crush on the Grinch?
当然不是
Of course not.
那不是我问的
I didn't ask you that.
是嘛
Right.
他那天回家不知道怎么搞的
For some reason, when he came home that day...
非常认真地在准备圣诞礼物
...he really got into the Christmas spirit for the first time.
太好了
Perfect!
Whoopsie!
好漂亮的传家之宝
What a lovely family heirloom!
爱的火焰
The fires of love!
放在她的圣诞树上刚刚好
This will be perfect on the top of her tree.
我爱玛莎
Oh, Martha! Oh, Christmas!
我爱圣诞节
明天要漂漂亮亮的来上学
I want you all to look your best tomorrow.
她不会喜欢你的
You don't have a chance with her.
你脸上都是毛
You're 8 years old and you have a beard!
礼物都送好了吗？
Has everyone given their gifts?
我还没 什么？
- I haven't. - What?
玛莎，圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas, Martha May.
你头上戴个袋子干嘛？
Why do you have a bag on your head?
八成礼物太烂，没脸见人
Probably because he's embarrassed by that hideodorous gift.
鬼灵精同学
Mr. Grinch...
请你把袋子拿掉
...please take the bag off.
对，把它脱掉
Yes, you.
Take it off.
把课本放下
Put the book down.
还有你的脚
And your foot.
你们看他的脸
Look at that hack job!
臭礼物
Stupid present!
臭树
Stupid tree!
我讨厌圣诞节
I hate Christmas!
那股怒气 那阵怒吼
- The anger. - The fury!
那身肌肉
The muscles!
他们实在太坏了，那样嘲笑他
It was a horrible day when they were so cruel to him.
我…
And...
看了都好难过
...I could hardly bear it.
我讨厌圣诞节，我讨厌它
I hate Christmas! I hate it!
那是我们最后一次看到他
And that was the last time we ever saw him.
最后一次
The very last time.
不管是因为他的心胸 还是他的鞋子
So, whatever the reason, his heart or his shoes...
他站在山顶，继续讨厌胡谷镇民
...he stood outside his cave...
...hating the Whos.
照名字顺序
Alphabetically.
艾瓦金胡
Aardvarkian Abakenezer Who...
我…
...I...
讨厌你
...hate you!
艾伦班森胡，我讨厌你
Aaron B. Benson Who, I hate you.
讨厌、讨厌、讨厌
Hate, hate, hate. Hate, hate, hate.
非常讨厌
Double hate.
全部都讨厌
Loathe entirely!
胡桃钳？
Nutcrackers?
又是他们的庆祝活动
It's their Whobilation.
他突然想到…
He snarled with a sneer.
明天就是圣诞节
Tomorrow is Christmas! It's practically here.
圣诞节到了
麦斯，把镇静剂拿来
Max!
Fetch me my sedative.
睡着了就不会胡思乱想
Now to take care of those pesky memories.
圣诞庆祝活动多，有吃又有玩
"Whobilation, plentiful with candy canes and pies
胡谷镇民聚一堂，开心过圣诞
"I can't wait to get there to eat some google fries
胡谷镇，胡谷镇
"Whobilation, Whobilation"
这次的庆祝我想过了 怎样？
- Dad? - Yeah.
I've been thinking about the Whobilation and I may do something drastic.
我可能会吓你们一跳
我没意见，你问你妈
That's fine, dear. Ask your mother.
她去哪了？ 老公
- Where did she go? - Honey!
老公，等我
Honey! Hi!
你看，可以拿来当圣诞灯饰
Look, I just found the cutest light for my Christmas display.
快点，我们要迟到了
Hurry up, we're gonna be late. Come on.
现在宣布
And now, the nominations...
胡谷镇民票选
...for that Who among us who best typifies...
担任圣诞男女主角
...the qualities of Whodom and Whodery...
最合适的人选
...the Whoville holiday cheermeister!
有人要提名吗？
Do I hear a nomination?
我提名鬼灵精
I nominate the Grinch!
- The Grinch? - The Grinch?
天哪
My, my, my.
阿卢，你女儿可真幽默
What an altruistic daughter you have there, Lou!
不客气
Thank you.
Cindy?
“胡谷镇民手册”
Let me quote a verse...
上面说过…
...from The Book of Who.
谢谢
Thank you.
“鬼灵精”三个字
"The term 'Grinchy' shall apply when Christmas spirit is in short supply."
代表欠缺圣诞精神
你还认为他适合担任吗？
Now, I ask you: Does that sound like our holiday cheermeister?
但是，镇长先生 镇民手册上面也说
True, Mr. May-Who. But The Book of Who says this too:
不论镇民长相如何
"No matter how different a Who may appear...
皆受到圣诞的欢迎
"...he will always be welcomed with holiday cheer."
是没错，可是上面还说…
Yes, the book also says, the...
鬼灵精
"The award...
不得接受此项荣誉
"...cannot go to the Grinch, because...
因为他一定会…搞砸
"...sometimes things get the lead-pipe cinch."
你骗人，上面没这么说
You made that up! It doesn't say that.
当然有
No, it does.
哪一页？
What page?
我忘记了，反正…
Lost my place, but it's...
上面说过 但是手册有说
It's in here!
But the book does say:
应该由最需要鼓励的人
"The cheermeister is the one who deserves a back slap or a toast.
来担任圣诞男主角
"And it goes to the soul at Christmas who needs it most."
我认为鬼灵精需要鼓励
And I believe that soul is the Grinch.
我相信大家和我一样
And if you're the Whos I hope you are, you will too.
都这么认为
她说得对
She's right!
随便你们
Fine.
你们要浪费提名人选
You people want to waste a perfectly good nomination...
是你们的事
...why, it's up to you.
不过我告诉你们
But I am telling you...
他死都不会下来的
...the Grinch will never come down.
他缺席的话，就由镇长担任
And when he doesn't, the Mayor will wear the crown.
也只好如此了
Well, more or less.
"Deck your heart with jollity
"Style your smile all Christmasy
"Flick some flocking on the tree
"Let there be Whobilation
"Bake the fruitcake, egg the nog
"Feed the flaming Wholtide log
"Baste the beast and gulp the grog
"Let there be Whobilation
滴答，滴答
"Tick, tock, tick, tock
圣诞时钟滴答响
"Counting down the Christmas clock
男女老幼
"Old, young, big, small"
讨厌的圣诞歌
Blast this Christmas music.
难听得要命
It's joyful and triumphant.
看谁够大声
Must drown them out!
没有用
Not working!
北风从胡谷镇上呼啸而过
The whipperwinds whipped high above the Who town.
一不留神，人就会滑下山谷
A trip or a slip you'd slide all the way down.
但是小女孩身负着一项使命
But this girl had a mission. She knew what to do.
勇敢的辛蒂要上山
She'd invite the Grinch herself, that brave Cindy Lou.
亲自邀请鬼灵精
敲啊，猴子，用力敲
Play, monkey! Play!
“滚开”
Howdy?
鬼灵精先生？
Mr. Grinch?
Mr. Grinch!
Hello?
对不起
Excuse me.
你好，小妹妹
Hello...
你好大胆，闯进鬼灵精的窝
...little girl.
How dare you enter...
...the Grinch's lair?
没礼貌、不要脸
The impudence! The audacity!
实在是无法无天
The unmitigated gall!
是你自找的，休怪我…
You called down the thunder...
...now, get ready for the boom!
手下无情
看我这次，怎么吓你
Gaze into the face of fear!
鬼灵精先生
Mr. Grinch...
你好，我叫辛蒂卢
...my name is Cindy Lou Who.
你看，现在怕了吧
You see?
Even now the terror is welling up inside you.
手脚发软了吧
我没有害怕
I'm not scared.
少来了，怕我是很正常的
Denial is to be expected in the face of pure evil.
我真的不怕
I don't think so.
否认？又来了一个神经大条的
Doubt?
Another unmistakable sign of the heebie-jeebies!
你这下完蛋了
Now you're doomed!
你快点逃
Run for your life...
我要发作了
...before I kill again!
我是疯子
I'm a psycho!
危险，小心
Danger! Danger!
也许你该休息一下
Maybe you need a time-out.
现在的小孩，电视电影看太多了
Kids today.
So desensitized by movies and television.
你要干嘛？
What do you want?
鬼先生
Mr. Grinch, I came to invite you...
我来邀请你，担任圣诞男主角
...to be holiday cheermeister.
圣诞什么东东？ 男主角
- "Holiday Whobie-what-y"? - Cheermeister.
男主角，与朋友共度佳节
"Cheermeister. Celebrate with friends."
真好笑
That's a good one.
我知道你讨厌圣诞节
I know you hate Christmas, but what if it's all just a misunderstanding?
万一只是一场误会呢？
无所谓 我自己也不相信圣诞节
- Don't care. - I myself am having some Yuletide doubts.
如果你愿意来胡谷镇
But maybe if you reunite with the Whos and be a part of Christmas--
一起庆祝圣诞节…
"Maybe if you reunite with the Whos and be a part of Christmas."
别傻了 我也许就会相信了
Grow up!
Then maybe it'll be all right for me, too!
抱歉，谈话时间结束 预约下次咨询
I'm sorry, your session is over.
Please make another appointment with the receptionist on the way out.
请找接待小狗 你一定要接受这个奖
Please, please. You have to accept the award.
什么奖？
Award?
你怎么不早说
You never mentioned an award!
有奖品
有啊，有奖杯跟其他的东西
Yeah, with a trophy and everything.
我赢了？ 你赢了
- And I won? - You won!
那表示有人输了 大概吧
- That means there were losers. - I guess.
你来的话… 全镇都输了
- So, if you come-- - A town full of losers!
我喜欢
I like it.
有人受不了打击吗？
Was anyone emotionally shattered?
说啊，你之前不是话很多 细节，说细节
Come on, a minute ago I couldn't shut you up! Details, details!
嗯，镇长不太高兴
The Mayor wasn't happy.
Oh, no.
梅玛莎也会去
Martha May will be there.
她也会去？
She will?
那她就会看到我，赢
And she'll see me.
A winner.
她会像苍蝇一样
She'll be on me like fleegle flies on a flat-faced floogle horse.
绕着我打转
玛莎，我不想让你难过
I'm sorry to disappoint you, Martha, baby, but the G train has left the station.
但是我们之间不可能了
你会来吗？
So, will you come?
好吧
All right.
不晓得是你可爱的眼睛
I don't know if it's that adorable twinkle in your eye...
还是你坚强的意志 让我想到当年的我
...or that nonconformist streak...
...that reminds me of a younger, less hairy me.
我被你打动了
But you've convinced me.
说不定，这次的圣诞庆祝
Who knows? This Whobilation could change my entire outlook on life!
会改变我的一生
真的？  才怪
- Really? - No.
终于找到你了，等下再堆雪人
There you are, honey.
You can make snow angels later.
圣诞庆祝就要开始了
We can't be late for the Whobilation!
那群镇民也真是的
The nerve of those Whos.
现在才通知我
Inviting me down there on such short notice.
就算我想去，也排不出时间来
Even if I wanted to go, my schedule wouldn't allow it.
四点，自怜
"4:00, wallow in self-pity.
四点半，发呆
"4:30, stare into the abyss.
五点，饥饿三十
"5:00, solve world hunger...
默默行善
"...tell no one.
五点半，鬼扯
"5:30, jazzercise.
六点半，独自晚餐，不能失约
"6:30, dinner with me." I can't cancel that again.
七点，自怨
"7:00, wrestle with my self-loathing."
都排满了
I'm booked.
如果把自怨的时间挪到九点
If I bumped the loathing to 9:00, I'd have time to lay in bed...
我还是可以准时上床，继续失眠
...stare at the ceiling and slip slowly into madness.
可是要穿什么呢？
But what would I wear?
这不是洋装，是苏格兰裙
It's not a dress, it's a kilt!
变态
Sicko!
太逊、太丑、太土了
Stupid.
Ugly.
Out of date.
什么嘛，要是没有合适的衣服
This is ridiculous.
If I can't find something nice to wear, I'm not going!
我就不去
决定了，我不去
That's it, I'm not going.
到了颁奖给圣诞男主角的时间了
It's time for our Holiday Cheermeister of the Year Award!
恭喜，鬼灵精先生
Congratulations, Mr. Grinch!
“胡谷镇军乐队”
他没来
He isn't here.
什么？
What?
他竟然没来？
He didn't show?
谁会想到呢？
Who could have predicted this?
好，我就去一下
All right. I'll swing by for a minute, allow them to envy me...
让他们恭喜我 吃点点心，然后闪人
...grab a handful of popcorn shrimp, and blow out of there.
万一被骗怎么办？
But what if it's a cruel prank? What if it's a cash bar?
万一要钱怎么办？
赚我的钱？还是去好了
How dare they?
但是要迟到一下，去，不去
All right, I'll go.
But I'll be fashionably late.
No. Yes. No. Yes. No!
去
Yes!
死都不去
Definitely not!
好吧，决定了
All right. I've made my decision!
我去，就这么办
I'm going, and that's that.
如果来得及
Had my fingers crossed.
也许我该丢铜板
Maybe I should flip a coin!
看来，只好由第二名替补
I guess the award goes to...
...the runner-up.
没错，一位圣诞精神的代表
That's right. A man for whom Christmas comes not once a year...
圣诞精神的化身
...but every minute of every day.
一位潇洒、正直的男士
A handsome, noble man.
一位割了两次扁桃腺的人
A man who has had his tonsils removed twice!
这说来话长
That's an interesting story.
事情是这样…
You see, what happened was--
你好，玛莎 他赶来了
Hello, Martha.
辛蒂 女儿
He made it!
- Cindy. - Honey!
Look--
好热闹，好热闹
Hot crowd. Hot crowd.
我是来…
I believe I'm here to...
领个什么奖的
...accept an award of some kind.
还有，那个小妹妹
And the child mentioned a check.
说过有奖金
我哪有说过 随便啦，快颁奖
- No, I didn't. - All right, then, give me the award.
快点，想等死我啊
Come on, while I'm young!
别担心，圣诞男主角
Don't you worry, Mr. Holiday Cheermeister, you'll get your award.
一定会颁奖给你
但首先，应该全家团聚
But first, a little family reunion.
供你吃
They nursed you. They clothed you.
供你穿的是她们
你的老妈子
Here they are...
...your old biddies!
你们还没死？
Are you two still living?
我们想死你了
We missed you!
罗丝，毛衣，毛衣
Rose. The sweater. The sweater, Rose.
毛衣？什么意思？我不要
Sweater? What are you talkin' about? No, I can't!
不要逼我
I can't do that!
不要乱摸
Don't touch me there!
圣诞宝座来啦
Put him in the Chair of Cheer!
圣诞宝座？
Chair of Cheer?
什么是圣诞宝座？
What's the Chair of Cheer?
你提都没提过 拜托，不要生气
You didn't tell me about the Chair of Cheer.
Please, Mr. Grinch.
我真的不行 我还没做好心理准备
No. I can't do it, honestly.
I'm not ready. It's too much, too soon!
圣诞男主角
It's that time of year.
现在坐上宝座接受欢呼
The Cheermeister's ride in the Chair of Cheer!
放我下来，不然我告你们
Put me down! I mean it!
你们要倒大霉了
I've got a lawyer.
There'll be hell to pay!
首先，你要担任评审
First, you'll put your taste buds to the test...
选出布丁比赛的冠军 布丁比赛的冠军
...as you judge the Who pudding cook-off!
先试我的 我吃不出来…
- Mine first. - I really don't know--
不，我的比较好
No, mine's the best!
你会喜欢的
You'll enjoy this!
这不是布丁
This is not pudding.
那是什么？
What is it?
这是我做的
This is mine. Yummy, yummy, yummy.
圣诞康加舞
Christmas conga!
这么晚，我该回去了
Look at the time. I really should be getting back.
跳就跳
All right!
水果蛋糕
Fruitcake, tra-la-la!
No.
软糖比赛
Fudge Judge.
我自己做的 是吗？
Made it myself.
我的也是 好
Yeah? Mine are homemade too.
Okay.
来啊，继续塞
Put it in. Bring it on!
没有了吗？
Is that all you got?
没有了吗？来啊
Is that all you got? Come on.
笨蛋，别挡路
Out of the way, slow-mo!
对不起，借过
Excuse me.
他是跳跳袋比赛第一名
He's number one in the sack race run!
第一名，我是第一名
Number one! I'm number one!
我是第一名
I'm number one!
没有小孩可以打败我
No child can beat the Grinch!
耶！
我赢了
I beat you.
He won!
终于到了大家期待已久的时刻
And now it's time for the moment we've all been waiting for.
对，我的奖品
Yes! My award.
还有奖金 没有奖金
- Write the check. - There's no check.
你确定？ 我记得别人告诉我有奖金
Are you sure? Because I thought I heard someone mention a check.
都说了，没有奖金
I said, there's no check. And now it's time...
现在该发礼物了
...for Present Pass-it-on!
按照惯例，从圣诞男主角开始
As always, we start with our Cheermeister.
圣诞刮胡刀
The gift of a Christmas shave.
你们看他的脸
Look at that hack job!
想起小时候啦
Yes, yes, yes. Good times!
小时候
Good times.
现在我要送份小礼物给我的最爱
And now, I have a little something for the love of my life.
Martha May...
希望你能成为，奥古斯胡夫人
...please become Mrs. Augustus May-Who.
Augustus...
只要你嫁给我
If you agree to be my wife...
不但一辈子吃穿不尽
...along with a lifetime supply of happiness, you'll also receive this:
而且还会得到…
一辆新车
It's a new car!
由胡谷镇的纳税人热情提供
Generously provided by the taxpayers of Whoville!
你意下如何？
What do you say, Martha?
你有廿秒钟的时间
You got 20 seconds on the clock.
这个，我…
I...
这些礼物非常吸引人
These gifts are quite dazzling.
那还用说
Of course they are.
这就是你们的目的？
That's what it's all about, isn't it?
你们的目的就是为了这个
That's what it's always been about!
礼物
Gifts!
Gifts.
Gifts, gifts, gifts.
想知道那些礼物去哪了吗？
You want to know what happens to your gifts?
都进了垃圾桶，到我家了
They all come to me. In your garbage.
听到没？都进垃圾桶了
You see what I'm saying?
In your garbage!
光是在垃圾场找到的领结 就够我上吊了
I could hang myself with all the bad Christmas neckties I found at the dump!
贪心
And the avarice.
什么都想要
The avarice never ends!
我要高尔夫球具，我要钻石
"I want golf clubs." "I want diamonds."
我要一匹小马，不要再把它卖掉
"I want a pony, so I can ride it twice, get bored, and sell it to make glue."
不是我要唱反调
Look, I don't want to make waves, but this whole Christmas season is...
但是所谓的圣诞节
实在是，烂透了
...stupid, stupid, stupid!
虽然烂
There is, however...
有一项小小的…
...one teeny-tiny...
圣诞传统
...Christmas tradition...
我觉得…
...I find...
非常有意义
...quite meaningful.
w寄生
Mistletoe.
乡巴佬，排队来亲吧
Now, pucker up and kiss it, Whoville!
有人剪头发了
Somebody's fabulous!
好，轮你们，往那边走
All right, your turn! Go on!
我们快走 不要
- Let's go! - No!
对不起，老先生 不介意我喝一口吧
Excuse me, old-timer.
Mind if I wet my whistle?
我，嗯…
那是我的好酒
That's my good stuff!
烧吧，尽量烧
Burn, baby! Burn!
好酷
胡谷镇的传统
The Whomanity!
我们快走 等一下
- Let's go! Come on! - No, wait!
想想办法 是
- Do something. - Right!
各单位注意，各单位注意
Calling all units. Calling all units.
计程车
Taxi!
因为我是绿色就不停？
It's because I'm green, isn't it?
停
Halt!
晚安，不介意我搭个便车吧
Evening, folks. Mind if I ride along?
你们最好挪一挪
You might want to scooch over.
算你们聪明
You did the right thing.
让开
Out of the way!
明天一定会屁股痛
That's gonna hurt in the morning.
要爆炸了
It's gonna blow!
你们没事吧？不如买顶帽子吧
You fellas all right?
How about a nice hat?
Lou?
我很伤心，阿卢
I'm hurt, Lou.
我并不是那么容易受伤的人
I'm hurt, and I don't hurt easily.
但是你们一家人…
But you and your family...
我实在…太失望了
I'm so...
...disappointed.
不如我们回到 原来的圣诞庆祝活动
Can we just get back to Christmas...
...the way it should be?
忘了鬼灵精
Grinch-less?
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas!
我只是希望大家能一起过圣诞节
I just wanted everybody to be together for Christmas.
真过瘾
I quite enjoyed that.
希望他们会再邀请我
I hope I get another invite soon.
幸好我们还有另外一棵圣诞树
Come on, come on!
Good thing we have a spare.
可怜的棕树
Suffering snorkelblatz!
他们太过份了
They're relentless!
再四个小时就是圣诞节了
Only four hours till Christmas!
是的，鬼灵精知道 所有胡谷镇的小朋友
Yes, the Grinch knew tomorrow all the Who girls and boys...
明天一起床 就会拿到他们的礼物
...would wake bright and early and rush for their toys.
接着就是，噪音
And then, the noise!
天哪，没完没了的噪音
The noise, noise, noise!
他们会敲锣打鼓
They'll bang on tong-tinglers.
会吹喇叭
They'll blow their floo-flounders.
会穿弹簧鞋乱冲，坐跳跳球乱跑
They'll crash on jang-jinglers and bounce on boing-bounders!
然后胡谷镇的男女老幼会一起
Then Whos young and old would sit down to a feast.
享用丰收的圣诞大餐
And they'll feast and they'll feast.
然后他们会吃个不停
And they'll feast, feast, feast, feast!
他们会吃胡谷布丁
They'll eat their Who pudding.
还有吃招牌烤肉
And rare Who roast beast!
另外我最不能忍受的一件事
But there's something I just cannot stand in the least.
天哪
Oh, no.
我开始语无伦次了
I'm speaking in rhyme!
我讨厌你们
Blast you Whos!
鬼灵精越是想到圣诞节
And the more the Grinch thought of what Christmas would bring...
就越是觉得…
...the more the Grinch thought:
我一定要阻止这件事
I must stop this whole thing.
一年又一年，我已经受够了
Why, for year after year I've put up with it now!
我要让他们过不到圣诞节
I must stop this Christmas from coming! But how?
怎么阻止？
用什么方法呢？
I mean, in what way?
狗狗的圣诞节已经到了
"Christmas is goin' to the dogs
我们切火鸡、倒酒来庆祝
"We're scoffing down the turkey and the grog
"Things are looking very good, it's true"
你在庆祝愉快的…
Are you having a holly, jolly...
白色圣诞吗？
...Christmas?
错
Wrong-o!
你不帮我没关系
If you're not going to help me...
至少你不要…
...then you might as well...
他突然想到，一个邪恶的主意
Then he got an idea.
An awful idea.
鬼灵精想到一个非常…
The Grinch got a wonderful...
邪恶的主意
...awful idea.
我知道该怎么做了
I know just what to do.
鬼灵精得意地笑着
The Grinch laughed in his throat.
他缝了件圣诞老人装和顶帽子
And he made a quick Santy Claus hat and a coat.
他不停地笑着
And he chuckled and clucked...
感到十分得意
...at this great Grinchy trick.
穿上外套和帽子 我就像圣诞老人了
With this coat and this hat, I'll look just like Saint Nick.
小气鬼是鬼灵精
"You're a mean one, Mr. Grinch
你非常难搞定
"You really are a heel
脾气坏又小心眼 不可爱又讨人厌
"You're as cuddly as a cactus and as charming as an eel
鬼灵精
"Mr. Grinch
你是黑心肝的
"You're a bad banana
老妖怪
"With a greasy black peel
承认吧，你是妖怪
"Just face the music, you're a monster
鬼灵精，你别想赖
"Mr. Grinch, yes, you are
你没心又没肝
"Your heart's an empty hole
你的思想有问题 你的人格有缺陷
"Your brain is full of spiders You got garlic in your soul
鬼灵精
"Mr. Grinch
我不敢惹你
"I wouldn't touch you with a
除非我活得不耐烦
"thirty-nine-and-a-half foot pole"
我要的是三英寸那支，不是这支
I asked for three-quarters, not five-eighths.
专心点
Stay focused!
“开始引擎测试”
你要是问胡谷镇上的居民
"You know, if you asked the who's who of Whoville
没人会否认
"No one would deny it"
“撞这点”
安全气囊反应有点慢
Air bag is a little slow.
所以说，不测试不行
But that's what these tests are for!
你是坏人
"You're a vile one
鬼灵精
"Mr. Grinch
你笑起来有蛀牙
"You have termites in your smile
你的亲切和善
"You have all the tender sweetness Of a seasick crocodile
让人恶心反胃
鬼灵精
"Mr. Grinch
“小气鬼”
"Given the choice between you
两者让我选择
我选让人恶心反胃
"I'd take the seasick crocodile"
胖家伙应该就快好了
Fat boy should be finishing up anytime now.
说到离群索居
Talk about a recluse.
为什么大家就欢迎他 每年来光临一次
He only comes out once a year, and he never catches any flak for it!
他住那么远八成是为了逃税
Probably lives up there to avoid the taxes.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas!
Oopsie.
忘记有糜鹿了
Forgot about the reindeer.
鬼灵精有没有因此而放弃？
Did that stop the old Grinch?
没有，他只是说…
No.
The Grinch simply said:
要是找不到糜鹿
If I can't find a reindeer...
那我就自制一只
...I'll make one instead.
小狗狗！
Oh, Max!
“请勿打扰” 于是他把麦斯叫来
So he called his dog Max...
找了一捆红线
...and he took some red thread...
在它头上绑了一只角
...and tied a big horn on top of his head.
好啦，你是糜鹿
All right.
这是动机，你叫鲁道夫
You're a reindeer. Here's your motivation.
你是红鼻子怪胎，没人喜欢你
You're Rudolph, a freak with a red nose, nobody likes you.
有一天圣诞老人看上你 你救了圣诞节
Then one day, Santa picks you and you save Christmas.
算了，我们来改写历史
No, forget that part. We'll improvise.
但是不要太夸张
Just keep it kind of loosey-goosey.
你讨厌圣诞节，所以要偷走
You hate Christmas! You're gonna steal it!
拯救圣诞的结局 太老土、太商业化了
Saving Christmas was a lousy ending. Way too commercial.
开始！
Action!
太棒了
Brilliant!
你拒绝戴假鼻子
You reject your own nose...
因为你不想帮人打广告
...because it represents the glitter of commercialism!
我怎么没想到？
Why didn't I think of that?
停拍，收工，关门，出发
Cut, print, check the gate. Moving on.
感觉…不错
That...
...feels...
...good.
笨狗，看我的
Here goes nothin', hot dog!
Wow!
“满油”
成功了
This is nuts!
目标正前方
On, Crasher! On, Thrasher!
全速前进
On, Vomit and Blitzkrieg!
完蛋了，我们死定了
We're gonna die!
我要吐了，吐完再死
I'm going to throw up, and then I'm gonna die!
妈，快来救我
Mommy, tell it to stop!
差点失去我的冷静
Almost lost my cool there.
窗外的雪静静地下着
All their windows were dark. Quiet snow filled the air.
居民们毫无戒心的睡着
All the Whos were all dreaming sweet dreams without care...
他来到镇上第一户人家
...when he came to the first little house on the square.
麦斯，欢迎光临胡谷镇
Welcome to Whoville, Max.
贝蒂
Betty?
贝蒂 干嘛？
- Betty? - What?
有没有听到声音？
Did you hear something?
是圣诞老人
It's Santa!
继续睡
Go right back to sleep.
走吧，麦斯，我们的第一站
Come on, Max. It's our first stop.
鬼灵精得意地偷笑
The old Grinchy Claus hissed.
他拿着空袋子，跳到屋顶上
And he climbed to the roof, empty bags in his fist.
他打算从烟囱滑下去
He'd slide down the chimney. A rather tight pinch.
既然圣诞老人都挤得进去
But if Santa could do it, then so could the Grinch.
他要尝试转体两圈半
He's planning a double-twisting interrupted forward-flying 2-and-a-half...
配合上抱膝动作
...with a combo tuck and pike.
属于高难度
High degree of difficulty.
他被卡住了一两下子
He got stuck only once, for a moment or two.
该死的体重，全在我的屁股上
Blasted water weight! Goes right to my hips.
接着他从壁炉探头出来
Then he stuck his head out of the fireplace flue.
拜托，小声一点
A little more stealth, please.
一排长袜挂在壁炉边
Where the little Who stockings all hung in a row.
这些袜子… 他笑着说
These stockings...
第一批送走
...he grinned...
...are the first thing to go.
伙伴们，吃饭时间
Okay, fellas. Show time.
然后他冲向冰箱
Then he slunk to the icebox.
冲？
Slunk?
他看到了招牌烤肉
He eyed the Whos' feast. He took the Who pudding.
他拿了胡谷布丁
他拿了招牌烤肉
He took the roast beast.
来啦！
Hike!
他把冰箱一扫而空
He cleaned out that icebox as quick as a flash.
连最后一罐马铃薯泥都不放过
Why, that Grinch, he even took their last can of Who hash.
他把所有的食物从烟囱送出去
Then he stuffed all the food up the chimney with glee.
接下来 鬼灵精笑着说…
And now...
...grinned the Grinch...
我要拿圣诞树走
...I'll stuff up the tree.
当他抓着树往壁炉走的时候
And the Grinch grabbed the tree, and he started to shove...
他听到清脆的声音在身后响起
...when he heard a small sound like the coo of a dove.
对不起
Excuse me.
鬼灵精被一名小女孩逮到了
The Grinch had been caught by this tiny Who daughter...
她刚好起床喝水
...who'd got out of bed for a cup of cold water.
圣诞老人 你拿我们的圣诞树干嘛？
Santa Claus? What are you doing with our tree?
但是鬼灵精太聪明、太狡猾了
But, you know, that old Grinch was so smart and so slick...
他马上想到了一个藉口
...he thought up a lie, and he thought it up quick.
哦，可爱的小妹妹
Why...
...my sweet little tot.
假圣诞老人骗她
The fake Santa Claus lied.
圣诞树上有粒灯泡坏了
There's a light on this tree...
...that won't...
就在这边
...light on one side.
所以我要带回我家去修
So I'm taking it home to my workshop, my dear.
我回去修好以后
I'll fix it up there...
再送回来给你
...and I'll bring it back here.
圣诞节的意义是什么？
Santa, what's Christmas really about?
报复
Vengeance!
我是说…
I mean...
礼物
...presents...
我猜吧
...I suppose.
我就是怕这样
I was afraid of that.
他骗过了小女孩
And his fib fooled the child.
拍拍她的头，帮她拿了杯水
Then he patted her head, and he got her a drink...
叫她回去睡觉
...and he sent her to bed.
圣诞老公公
Santa?
干嘛？ 别忘了鬼灵精家
- What? - Don't forget the Grinch.
他是脾气不好，又长了一身毛
I know he's mean and hairy and smelly.
虽然他的手又冰又凉
His hands might be cold and clammy.
可是我觉得他蛮可爱的
But I think he's actually kind of sweet.
可爱？
Sweet?
你认为他可爱？
You think he's sweet?
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas, Santa.
当辛蒂卢拿杯子回房间的时候
And when Cindy Lou went up with her cup...
好小孩
Nice kid.
可惜不会看人
Bad judge of character.
他把圣诞树从烟囱塞出去
...he went to the chimney and stuffed the tree up.
“圣诞老人入口”
最后还拿走他们的木材
And the last thing he took was the log for their fire.
墙上只留下挂钩和电线
On their walls he left nothing but some hooks and some wire.
他留下的一点食物
And the one speck of food that he'd left in the house...
还不够老鼠塞牙缝
...was a crumb that was even too small for a mouse.
然后他一脸奸笑、蹑手蹑脚
Then he slithered and slunk, with a smile most unpleasant...
挨家挨户地搜刮所有的礼物
...around each Who home, and he took every present.
清仓大拍卖，一件也不留
Clearance sale.
Everything must go.
又怎么了？
What now?
你有亲过割了两次 扁桃腺的人吗？
Martha...
...have you ever kissed a man who lost his tonsils twice?
没有，傻瓜
No, silly!
但是我一直希望有这样的经验
But it's an experience that I've always longed for.
吻我吧，傻瓜
Kiss me, you fool!
“没油”
你笑什么笑？
What are you laughing at...
鲁道夫
...Rudolph?
麦斯，全靠你了
It's all you, Maxie!
三千英尺高的松饼山峰上
3,000 feet up, up the side of Mount Crumpit...
他驾着车到山顶倒礼物
...he rode with his load to the tiptop to dump it.
我们成功了
We did it!
We did it! We did it!
还不错吧？麦斯
That wasn't so bad, was it, Max?
他们现在应该醒了
They'll be waking up now.
我知道他们会干嘛
And I know just what they'll do.
那些胡谷镇的居民
All those Whos...
...down in Whoville...
一定会哭
...will all cry.
太丢脸，连我都被抢
What an embarrassment! I've been robbed!
镇长大人？天哪
Mayor May-Who? Oh, dear.
真想不出来有谁会干这种事
I wonder who could have done this.
告诉你们吧
Tell you people one thing:
邀请鬼灵精
Invite the Grinch...
圣诞节就没了
...destroy Christmas.
邀请鬼灵精，圣诞节就没了
Invite the Grinch...
...destroy Christmas!
但是有人听吗？
But did anyone listen to me?
我有 没有
- I did. - No.
你们宁可听…
You choose to listen...
一个搞不清状况的小女孩
...to a little not-to-be-taken-seriously girl...
什么都不懂的小女孩
...who hasn't even grown into her nose yet.
辛蒂，我希望你现在高兴了
Cindy, I hope you're very proud...
...of what you've done.
就算她没有，我有
If she isn't, I am.
我很高兴他拿走我们的礼物
I'm glad he took our presents.
什么？ 我…
- What? - I...
我…我很高兴
他很高兴，你很高兴
- I'm glad. - He's glad.
你很高兴我们什么都没有
You're glad. You're glad everything is gone.
你很高兴鬼灵精…
You're glad that the Grinch virtually wrecked...
彻底破坏了
不是破坏，是摧毁了圣诞节
No, not wrecked, pulverized Christmas.
你的意思是不是这样？
Is that what I'm hearing?
镇长先生，没有人能破坏圣诞节
You can't hurt Christmas, Mr. Mayor...
圣诞节不是礼物、比赛 不是漂亮的灯饰
...because it isn't about the gifts or the contests or the fancy lights.
这就是辛蒂想要让大家知道的
That's what Cindy's been trying to tell everyone.
还有我，她想要让我知道
And me. She's been trying to tell me.
你有毛病啊？她只是个小孩
What is wrong with you? This is a child.
她是我的小孩，而且她是对的
She's my child.
And she happens to be right, by the way.
圣诞节我需要的是我的家人 不是别的
I don't need anything more for Christmas than this right here, my family.
圣诞快乐，各位 圣诞快乐
- Merry Christmas, everybody! - Merry Christmas!
圣诞快乐，大帅哥
Merry Christmas, you hunk of burnin' Who!
饶了我吧
Give me a break.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas!
鬼灵精先生？
Mr. Grinch?
我伟大计划的最后一步
Now for the final note in my symphony...
倒掉所有的烂礼物
...of downright nasty not-niceness!
完成我的杰作
The crescendo of my odious opus!
太棒了
哭泣和哀求
The wailing and the gnashing of teeth.
咒骂和怒吼
The bellowing of the bitterly bummed out!
就像是对我的歌颂
It'll be like music to my ears!
鬼灵精听到雪中传来了声音
Then the Grinch heard a sound rising over the snow.
从小声变得越来越大声
It started in low. Then it started to grow.
但那声音听起来并不悲伤
But the sound wasn't sad.
反而非常快乐
Why, this sounded merry.
非常，非常地快乐
But it was merry.
胡谷镇的男女老幼
Very.
Every Who down in Whoville, the tall and the small...
没有了礼物仍旧在唱歌
...were singing without any presents at all.
他没有办法阻止圣诞节
He hadn't stopped Christmas from coming.
无论如何，还是来了
It came.
Somehow or other, it came just the same!
鬼灵精先生？
Mr. Grinch?
鬼灵精呆站在雪地上
And the Grinch, with his Grinch feet ice-cold in the snow...
觉得非常迷惘
...stood puzzling and puzzling.
怎么可能？
How could it be so?
明明没有蝴蝶结
It came without ribbons!
没有标签
It came without tags!
没有包装，没有盒子 怎么还是有圣诞节？
It came without packages, boxes or bags!
他怎么想都想不通
And he puzzled and puzzled...
想到他头都痛了
...till his puzzler was sore.
然后他想到一件事
Then the Grinch thought of something...
以前从来没想到过
...he hadn't before.
也许圣诞节
Maybe...
他想…
...Christmas...
...he thought...
和礼物一点关系都没有
...doesn't come from a store.
圣诞节
Maybe Christmas...
也许
...perhaps...
有更深的意义
...means a little bit more.
救救我
Help me!
我…
I'm...
有感觉了
...feeling!
后来发生的事
And what happened then...
据胡谷镇的居民说
...well, in Whoville they say...
鬼灵精狭窄的心胸
...that the Grinch's small heart...
在那天变大了三倍
...grew three sizes that day.
我是怎么了？
What's happening to me?
我…
I'm all...
觉得好感动
...toasty inside.
而且我在哭
And I'm leaking.
喔，麦斯
Oh, Max.
我爱你
I love you!
好了，别舔了，滚开
All right, that's enough. Knock it off. Beat it!
别猴急，我需要慢慢来
Get out of here!
One step at a time.
糟了，雪橇，还有礼物
No. The sleigh. The presents.
我绝对不能让雪橇掉下去
They'll be destroyed!
And I care!
我竟然会关心这种事？
What is the deal?
等一下
Wait!
绝对不行
This can't happen!
千万不能让它掉下去
It shouldn't! It couldn't! It mustn't! It wouldn't!
绝对不可以掉下去
Not now, not then, not ever again!
不！
No!
算了
Oh, well.
反正只是玩具
It's just toys, right?
你好，鬼灵精先生
Hi, Mr. Grinch!
Cindy Lou!
你在上面干嘛？
What are you doing up there?
我来看你的
I came to see you. No one should be alone on Christmas.
你不应该一个人过圣诞节
No!
辛蒂卢，不要怕
I got you, Cindy Lou!
你办到了
You did it!
起飞，着地
Spread eagle! Nailed it!
你没事吧？ 太小看我了
Are you all right?
这么好的天气，这么棒的雪
Are you kiddin'?
The sun is bright and the powder's bitchin'!
坐过去，换我来
Now scoot over! It's my turn to drive!
最好慢一点
I'd better slow this buggy down!
我们要撞车了
- We're gonna crash! - Now you listen to me, young lady!
你听我说
就算我们撞得乱七八糟
Even if we're horribly mangled...
也不准在圣诞节愁眉苦脸的
...there'll be no sad faces on Christmas.
那是什么？ 救命
What is it?
辛蒂！
Help!
鬼灵精！
- Cindy! - Grinch?
我的女儿
My baby!
玛莎，抓住另外一头
Grab an end.
这些灯和你的睡衣很配
By the way, these lights match your outfit perfectly.
这下子麻烦大了
This could be more difficult to negotiate.
胡谷镇，我来啦
Heads up, Whoville!
快点，他来了
Hurry! Here he comes!
快闪开，我没保险
Out of the way! I have no insurance!
糟了
Yeah!
快逃，我停不下来
Run for your lives!
Watch out, I can't stop!
爸，让开 爸，快让开
- Daddy, move! - Dad, move it!
多谢帮忙
Thanks for the help.
- Hi, Daddy! - Hi, Cindy, honey!
大家圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas...
...one and all!
Cindy!
Mommy!
好啦
All right.
怎么回事啊？
What do we have here?
警官，问得好
You got me, Officer!
是我做的
I did it!
圣诞礼物是我，鬼灵精偷的
I'm the Grinch that stole Christmas.
我很抱歉
And I'm...
...sorry.
你不抓我吗？
Aren't you gonna cuff me?
不制伏我？不拿喷雾器喷我？
Put me in a choke hold? Blind me with pepper spray?
你都听到了，他承认了
You heard him, Officer. He admitted it.
快拿喷雾器喷他
- I'd go with the pepper spray. - Yes, I heard him, all right.
没错，我是有听到
他说他很抱歉
He said he was sorry.
再说，东西全都找回来了
Besides, it looks like everything is all here and accounted for.
你们帮忙说句话啊
Help me out here, people.
玛莎？
Martha?
圣诞快乐，奥古斯胡
Merry Christmas, August May-Who!
我有样东西要给你
I'm afraid I do have something for you!
你的戒指，还你
Your ring back.
抱歉，我喜欢的…
Sorry...
...but my heart belongs to...
是别人
...someone else.
别介意
No hard feelings?
老兄，圣诞节，高兴点
Cheer up, dude. It's Christmas.
鬼灵精先生，圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas, Mr. Grinch.
你的脸颊…
Your cheek is so...
我知道，毛毛的
I know.
不是 油油的？
Hairy?
- No. - Greasy?
臭臭的？我有长痘痘吗？
Stinky? Do I have a zit?
No.
暖暖的
Warm.
"Fah who foraze, dah who doraze
欢迎圣诞
"Welcome, Christmas, come this way
请进来
"Fah who foraze, dah who doraze
欢迎圣诞
"Welcome, Christmas, Christmas Day
圣诞节
欢迎，欢迎
"Welcome, welcome, fah who rahmus
"Welcome, welcome, dah who dahmus
圣诞节就在我们手中
"Christmas Day is in our grasp
只要我们双手紧握
"So long as we have hands to clasp
"Fah who ray-moo ya-who hee haw
欢迎圣诞，唱出你的…
"Welcome, Christmas, bring your cheer
欢呼 欢呼
"Fah who foraze
"Dah who doraze, welcome all Whos
欢迎胡谷镇所有的居民
远…
"far
或
"and
近
"near"
他送回来所有的礼物和食物
So he brought back the toys and the food for the feast.
而鬼灵精，他亲自切了烤肉
And he, he himself, the Grinch...
...carved the roast beast.
好耶！
Yeah!
没有比过节更棒的了
There's nothin' like the holidays.
有谁要鸡胗？ 我要
- Who wants the gizzard? - I do!
太慢了，我自己要
Too late!
That'll be mine.
终于找到
"Where are you, Christmas?
圣诞影踪
"I think I've found you
愿此刻永远停留
"This time I'll make you stay
歌声唱起
"All will be singing
铃声响起
"Bells will be ringing
永远都是
"Now and forever
圣诞节
"Christmas Day"